让我们总结一下我们在本次讲座中谈到的一些要点。
Let's summarize some of the points that we’ve talked about in this lecture.
今天我们理所当然地认为我们可以使用GPS来确定我们在任何地方的位置
Today we take for granted that we can use GPS to determine our position anywhere on
这个星球的表面，但它是一种相对较新的技术。它才开始运作
the surface of the planet, but it is a relatively recent technology. It only became operational
在1994年，只有在2000年才能以合理的准确度为公众提供。
in 1994, and only became available at reasonable accuracy for the general public in the year 2000.
在GPS出现之前，精确地在行星表面或外太空中导航
Before the advent of GPS, navigating precisely on the surface of the planet or in outer space
非常困难，使用的技术称为惯性导航，
was very very difficult, and the technology that was used was called inertial navigation,
这包括测量车辆的加速度和角速度，并进行积分
and that involved measuring the acceleration and angular velocity of a vehicle, and integrating
随着时间的推移确定位置。
that over time to determine the position.
惯性导航系统的关键部件是：惯性测量单元;
The key components of an Inertial Navigation System are: an inertial measurement unit;
它包含测量加速度，磁场和角速度的传感器
which contains the sensors that measure acceleration, magnetic field, and angular velocity, and
什么叫做航位推算软件;它接收那些信号并将它们集成在一起
what’s called dead reckoning software; that takes those signals and integrates them over
时间不断更新车辆的姿势。
time to continually update the pose of the vehicle.
在简单的水平上，我们可以认为加速度计是弹簧内部的质量
At a simplistic level we can consider that an accelerometer is a mass on a spring inside
一个小盒子。如果我们做代数，我们可以证明弹簧的延伸是线性的
a little box. If we do the algebra we can show that the extension of the spring is linearly
与装置的加速度和重力加速度成比例。加速度计
proportional to the acceleration of the device and the gravitational acceleration. An accelerometer
静止在地球上表示在垂直或向上方向上加速1g。
at rest on earth indicates an acceleration of 1g in the vertical or upward direction.
这有点违反直觉，因为当我们放弃某些东西时它会加速
This is a little bit counter-intuitive, because when we drop something it is going to accelerate
在向下的方向。静止加速度计向上测量1g。这是一个
in the downward direction. The accelerometer at rest measures 1g upwards. And this is a
等价原则的结果。地球表面的加速度计
consequence of the equivalence principle. An accelerometer on the surface of the earth
或安装在火箭上的加速度计以1g向上加速，两者都表示加速度
or an accelerometer mounted in a rocket accelerating upwards at 1g, both of them indicate an acceleration
1克
of 1g.
许多设备，例如我的手机，包含三个测量加速度的加速度计
Many devices, for example my phone, contain three accelerometers which measure acceleration
在连接到我的手机的坐标系B的x，y和z方向上。我可以使用
in the x, y and z directions of a coordinate frame B attached to my phone. I can use the
在坐标系B中测量手机中加速度的分量来确定
components of acceleration measured in the phone in coordinate frame B to determine the
相对于蓝色坐标系0，手机的滚动和俯仰。
roll and pitch of the phone with respect to the blue coordinate frame 0.
地球包含一个巨大但相当弱的磁铁，但磁铁的磁极不是
The earth contains a gigantic but fairly weak magnet, but the poles of that magnet are not
不变。它们随着时间而变化。指南针有一个指向北方的针
constant. They change with time. A compass has a needle which points towards the north
磁极，但北极磁极与北极地理极不同。
magnetic pole, but the north magnetic pole is different to the north geographic pole.
在地球表面的任何特定点，我们都可以建立一个右撇子
At any particular point on the surface of the earth we can establish a right-handed
坐标框架，其中一个轴指向北地理极点，另一个轴指向
coordinate frame where one axis points towards the north geographic pole, another axis points
垂直向下朝向行星的中心，另一个轴指向行星的中心
vertically downwards towards the centre of the planet, and the other axis points in the
地理东方向。地球的磁场矢量在这里用红色箭头表示，
geographic east direction. The earth’s magnetic field vector is shown here by a red arrow,
并且可以通过两个角度来描述该坐标系。磁偏角
and it can be described with respect to this coordinate frame by two angles. Magnetic declination
是两个方向之间的差异;真正的北方向和方向
is the difference between two directions; the direction of true north and the direction
磁北极-指南针指向的方向。另一角是磁性的
of magnetic north - the direction that the compass points in. The other angle is magnetic
倾斜，这是磁场矢量相对于的角度
inclination, and that’s the angle that the magnetic field vector makes with respect to
局部水平面。它也被称为磁浸。
a local horizontal surface. It’s also referred to as magnetic dip.
为了确定偏航角-这是身体面向的方向
In order to determine the yaw angle - that’s the direction that the body is facing with
尊重磁北-我们需要结合两个传感器的信息。我们确定
respect to magnetic north - we need to combine information from two sensors. We determine
使用加速度计的车身侧倾角和俯仰角，然后我们使用这些组件
the roll and pitch angle of the body using the accelerometers, and then we use the components
在身体上感知的磁场，将其与我们对当地的了解相结合
of the magnetic field sensed onboard the body, combine that with what we know about the local
磁倾角和局部磁场强度来确定偏航
magnetic inclination angle, and the local magnetic field strength to determine the yaw
角度。
angle.
旋转盘具有一些有趣的动态特性。其中之一是我们可以使用
A spinning disc has some interesting dynamic properties. One of these is that we can use
它将角速度-欧米茄-绕蓝轴转换成扭矩-tau
it to convert an angular velocity - omega - about the blue axis, into a torque - tau
-关于红轴。
- about the red axis.
我们可以通过测量施加在支撑轴上的力来测量该扭矩
We can measure that torque by measuring the forces that are exerted on the axle that supports
旋转的圆盘。如果我们知道诸如盘的转动惯量之类的参数
the rotating disc. If we know the parameters such as the rotational inertia of the disc
和盘的旋转速度，然后我们可以确定欧米茄，旋转速度
and the rotational velocity of the disc, then we can determine omega, the rotational velocity
这种陀螺仪传感器。
of this gyroscopic sensor.
有趣的是，我们的身体中存在加速度计和陀螺仪的生物等价物。
Interestingly there are biological equivalents of accelerometers and gyroscopes in our bodies.
在我们的每个耳朵中，我们有两个加速度计和三个测量运动的陀螺仪
In each of our ears we have two accelerometers and three gyroscopes which measure the motion
我们的身体，这与我们大脑中的视觉信息相结合，以便了解
of our body, and that’s integrated with visual information in our brain to understand
我们如何走向世界。
how we are moving with respect to the world.
最后，我们研究了如何计算旋转矩阵的导数。这是它的产物
Finally we looked at how to compute the derivative of a rotation matrix. It’s the product of
两个矩阵：它是一个偏斜对称矩阵乘以原始旋转矩阵。
two matrices: it’s a skew-symmetric matrix multiplied by the original rotation matrix.
斜对称矩阵是根据身体的角速度计算出来的;那就是
The skew-symmetric matrix is computed on the angular velocity of the body; that’s the
矢量L关于身体瞬间旋转乘以旋转速度
vector L about which the body is instantaneously rotating multiplied by the rate of rotation
关于那个轴。
about that axis.
斜对称矩阵具有许多有趣的属性。特别是它
The skew-symmetric matrix has got a number of interesting properties. In particular it’s
单数。也就是说，它的确定值总是等于0，它的转置是负数
singular. That is, its determinate is always equal to 0, and its transpose is the negative
自身的价值。在三维的情况下，如此处所示，我们可以清楚地看到零对角线，
value of itself. In the case of three dimensions, as shown here, we can clearly see a zero diagonal,
以及矩阵只包含三个独特元素x，y和z的事实
and the fact that the matrix only contains three unique elements, x, y and z, Each of
出现一次带有正号，一次出现负号。
which appear once with a positive sign, and once with a negative sign.